아냐, 끝났어, 됐어
No, no, we're done!
The One With the Dozen Lasagnas
이모, 화 내지 마세요!
Aunt Silv, stop yelling!
채식주의자를 위한 걸 원하면
야채 라자냐를 만들게요
If you'd told me
vegetarian lasagna...
... I would've made
vegetarian lasagna.
고기는 띄엄띄엄 보일테니까
긁어내고 드세요
The meat's only every third layer.
Maybe you could scrape.
정말 이 육아책 다 읽었어?
Ross, did you really read
all these baby books?
여자 자궁에 혼자 떨어져
나침반이 없어도...
You could plunk me down in
any woman's uterus, no compass...
길을 찾아 나올 수 있어
...and I could find my way
out like that!
이것 좀 봐!
태반을 먹는 사람들도 있대
This is cool.
It says in some parts of the world
people eat the placenta.
더 이상 못 먹겠어
And we're done with the yogurt.
Sorry.
미안
난 부탁 받고 하는 거지
요리사가 아니에요
I did this as a favor.
I am not a caterer.
대체 라자냐를
어떻게 하라는 거예요?
What do you want me to do
with a dozen lasagnas?
이모, 욕하지 마세요
Nice talk, Aunt Silv.
그 입으로 이모부와
키스하시죠?
You kiss Uncle Freddie
with that mouth?
아기가 지금 이만한 크기래
Ross, listen. Do you know that right
now your baby is only this big?
요게 네 아기래!
This is your baby.
" Hi, Daddy. "
안녕, 아빠!
Hello.
안녕!
" How come you don't live with Mommy? "
아빠는 왜 엄마랑 안 살아요?
엄마는 왜 여자랑 살죠?
" How come Mommy lives
with that other lady? "
레즈비언이 뭐예요?
"What's a lesbian? "
자기, 그건 '포커노즈'야
Honey, you can say it. Poconos.
포, 커, 노, 즈
Poconos. It's like " poke a nose. "
아... 포, 커, 노, 즈
Poke a nose.
포커노즈에 가니?
-So did I hear Poconos?
-Yes.
응, 우리 언니가 주말에
놀러가라고 했어
My sister's giving us her place
for the weekend.
First weekend together.
둘이 첫 여행이구나!
- 많이 발전했네
- 모르겠어
-It's a big step.
-I know.
주말 여행은 별 거 아냐
-It's just a weekend. Big deal.
-Wasn't this supposed to be a fling?
서로 질릴 때 안 됐나?
지금쯤 그럴 때잖아
Shouldn't it be...
...flung by now?
지겨운 건 아닌 것 같고...
We are way past a "fling. "
연애 소설에 보면 이런 기분을
표현 한 게 있던데...
I' m feeling things I've read about
in Danielle Steel books.
그러니까,
그이와 함께 있으면...
When l' m with him,
l' m just totally....
진저리가 나겠지, 온몸에서
Nauseous.
I' m physically nauseous.
나보고 어쩌라는 거야?
이민국에 전화라도 해?
What am I supposed to do?
Call lmmigration?
그것도 괜찮네
I could call lmmigration.
저게 뭐지?
이리 와봐
뭔데?
What?
못생긴 남자가
인형놀이 한다
Ugly Naked Guy is making
shadow puppets.
링컨 대통령인가봐
Look, it's Abraham Lincoln.
재밌겠다
Oh, right!
Go. Go!
난 아기가 좋아, 작은 발가락
작은 손가락이 꼼지락...
I love babies with
their little baby shoes...
...and their little baby toes
and their little hands....
제발 그만 좀 해
말도 꺼내지마!
Okay, you' re gonna have to stop that.
Forever.
새로 하나 사자
Need a new table.
그럴까?
You think?
- 왔어? 들어와
- 안녕
-Come on in.
-Hello.
육아책하고, 모니카가 만든
사랑의 라자냐야
I brought the books...
...and Monica sends her love
along with this lasagna.
고마워
Great! Is it vegetarian?
Because Susan doesn't eat meat.
수잔이 채식주의자인데
야채 넣은 거지?
틀림없이 그럴걸
I' m pretty sure that it is.
19주면 가슴이 커지기
시작한대
Nineteen weeks, the breasts
are starting to swell.
책에서 봤어
According to the literature.
-I got the results of the amnio.
-T ell me. Is everything...?
오늘 병원에 다녀왔어
말해봐, 어떻대?
- 아주 건강하게 잘 큰대
- 잘됐어! 다행이다
-T otally and completely healthy.
-That is great!
둘이 휴이 루이스하고 친해?
When did you and Susan
meet Huey Lewis?
우리 친구 타냐야
That's our friend T anya.
그래, 친구 타냐...
Of course, it's your friend T anya.
성별은 궁금하지 않아?
-Don't you wanna know about the sex?
-The sex?
성별?
두 사람 이미지를 합하고
거기에 타냐까지 더하면...
I' m having enough trouble with
the image of you and Susan together.
But when you throw in T anya....
아기 성별 말이야
The sex of the baby, Ross.
아기 성별?
You know the sex of the baby?
- 알고 싶어?
- 아니
-Want to know?
-No.
알고 싶지 않아
난 모르고 싶어
I don't want to. Absolutely not.
You shouldn't know until
you look down there...
아기를 낳는 순간에
어머, 나왔어! 그래야지
...and see, " Oh, there it is. "
Or isn't.
- 안녕, 로스
- 수잔
-Hello, Ross.
-Susan.
벌써 들었어?
So?
So did you hear?
응, 들었어
아주 양호하대
Yes, we did.
Everything's A-Okay.
정말 좋다
Oh, that's so cool!
다 좋대
It really is.
- 성별도 들었어?
- 당연하지
Do we know?
We certainly do.
It's going to be a
- 아기는...
- 잠깐, 숙녀분들...
Hello?
여기 이 남자는
알고 싶지 않사옵니다
A guy who doesn't wanna know
is standing here.
그럼, 우리가 원하는 대로니?
Well, is it what
we thought it would be?
어이, 나 좀 봐, 그럼...
뭘 원했는데?
What?
What did we think it'd be?
안돼! 알고 싶지 않아
I don't wanna know.
Don't wanna know.
난 이만 가보는 게 좋겠어
I should probably just go.
- 책 고마워
- 고맙긴, 뭘
-Well, thanks for the books.
-No problem. Okay.
잘 있어
Susan.
누구한테 먼저 알릴까?
너네 가족? 아님 데본?
Who should we call first?
Your folks or Deb and Rhona?
누구세요?
Hello?
됐어,
난 알고 싶지 않아
Never mind.
I don 't wanna know.
내 탁자였으니까
내가 사야된다는 거야?
Because it was my table,
I have to buy a new one?
그게 이치지
-That's the rule.
-What rule? There's no rule.
이치? 무슨 이치?
네 잘못 때문이잖아!
-You owe me a table.
-How did you get there?
그게 무슨 소리야?
네가 탁자에서 안젤라와
난리 치기 전엔, 튼튼했어
It was fine until your breakfast
adventure with Angela Delvecio.
You knew about that?
다 들었냐?
네가 버터에 남겨놓은 흔적도
봤는데, 설명해 주랴?
The impressions in the butter
left little to the imagination.
됐어, 우리가 헤어질 땐?
How about if we split it?
- 우리가 공동으로 구입할 경우?
- 응
-What do you mean, buy it together?
-Yeah.
벌써 마음의 준비를 해야돼?
-Do you think we' re ready for that?
-Why not?
그럼?
어쨌든 약속은 해두자
이사를 가게되면 어쩔 거야?
It's a big commitment.
What if one of us wants to move out?
- 왜? 너 이사가?
- 난 이사 안 가
-You' re moving out?
-l' m not.
나가고 싶을 땐 미리 말해
-You'd tell me if you were, right?
-Yes.
- 알았어, 전에 같이 살던 킵이...
- 그 녀석 얘긴 다 알아
-It's just, with my last roommate
-I know all about Kip.
탁자를 같이 샀는데
We bought a hibachi, then he ran off
and got married. Things got ugly.
결혼이라도 하게 되면
끝이 안 좋을 거야
하나 묻자
Let me ask you something.
Was Kip a better roommate than me?
킵이 나보다 나았니?
관두자
Oh, don't do that.
스케줄이 바뀌었어요
There's changes in your schedule.
4시 허브 마사지를
4시 반으로 옮겼어요
Your 4:00 herbal massage is at 4:30.
써머필드 양이 5시 반
지압을 취소했어요
And Miss Summerfield
canceled her 5:30 shiatsu.
알았어요
Thanks.
Oh, here comes your 3:00.
3시 손님 왔어요
손님을 차별하면 안되지만
너무 잘 생겼네요
I don't mean to sound unprofessional,
but Yum!
본 조르노, 피비
파올로! 안녕
웬일이야?
Paolo! Hi! What are you doing here?
당신이 마사지한다고 들었어
Rachella tell me you...
... massage?
레이첼이 말했군
맞아...
Well, Rachella's right.
Oh, okay.
무슨 말인지 모르겠어
아무튼 시작하자
I don't know what you just said,
so let's start.
옷을... 벗어야해?
I am...
... being naked?
좋을 대로 해
어떤 사람들은 벗고 해
That's your decision.
Some people prefer to take off
홀딱 벗을 필요는 없어
Being naked!
왜 알고 싶지 않아?
난 알고 싶을 거 같은데
I can't believe you don't
wanna know. I couldn't not know.
의사가 알고,
캐롤과 수잔도 알고...
If the doctor knows,
Carol and Susan know
나도 알아
And Monica knows.
내가 모르는 걸
네가 어떻게 알아?
How? I don't even know.
캐롤이 음식 잘 먹었다고
전화했을 때, 내가 물어봤지
Carol called to thank me
for the lasagna. She told me.
뭐랬는데?
So what's it gonna be?
이제 내 친구도 아는데
나만 모르는군
-Oh, great! Now he knows.
-l' m just excited about being an aunt.
미안해
고모가 되는 게 너무 신나
삼촌은 어때?
Or an uncle.
안녕, 피비!
-Hey, Phoebe.
-Hey, Pheebs.
좋아
Fine!
- 무슨 일 있어?
- 없어!
-What's the matter?
-Nothing. I' m just out of sorts.
미안, 제정신이 아냐
그럼 내 정신 좀 빌려가
난 자주 안 쓰거든
Well, you can use some of my sorts.
I rarely use them.
여기 카푸치노 언제 나와요?
Can we get some cappuccino
over here?
어머, 깜빡했다
Oh, right! That's me!
가구점이 7시에 닫는대, 가자
That table place closes at 7. Come on.
알았어
Fine.
왜 그래?
What is it?
파올로 알지?
-All right. You know Paolo?
-l' m familiar with his work.
그 녀석 잘 알지, 왜?
나한테 추근댔어
He made a move on me.
- 가게가 쉬는 날이래
- 커피 더 줄래?
-The store will be open tomorrow.
-More coffee, please.
어떻게 했는데?
Well, what happened?
마사지를 받으러 왔는데...
He came in for a massage,
and everything was fine until....
처음엔 괜찮았는데...
세상에!
-Oh, my God.
-Are you sure?
정말이야?
응, 정말이야
Oh, yeah. I' m sure.
그런데 갑자기 그 손이
싫지 않은 거야
And all of a sudden, his hands
weren't the problem anymore.
- 그러니까...
- 그러니까 좋았다는 뜻이야
Was it...?
Boy Scouts could've camped
under there.
Wow.
그래서 어쨌는데?
-What did you do?
-I dealt with it like a professional.
프로로서 잘 해결했지
뭔데?
" Ooh, " what?
- 터만이...
- 그 여배우?
ma Thurman.
-The actress!
-Uma Thurman!
그거야, 레이첼
Thanks, Rach.
이제 어쩔 건데?
-What'll you do?
-You have to tell her.
레이첼한테 말해!
말해 줘
친구로서 도덕적 양심이자
여성 동지의 의무지
It's your moral obligation as a friend,
as a woman. It's a feminist issue.
그렇지? 그렇지?
Guys?
맞아, 말해야돼
-You have to.
-Feminist issue? That's where I went.
여성 동지!
바로 내 전문이야
- 내가 욕먹을 거야
- 당연하지...
-She is gonna hate me!
-Yeah, well....
빨리 고를래? 그냥 골라
저건 어때?
Will you pick one?
Just pick one.
-Here, how about that one?
-That's patio furniture.
저건 베란다용이야
그래서? 거실에서 베란다
기분을 느낄 수 있잖아
So what? Like people will come in
and think, " Oh, l' m outside again. "
좋아, 새 무늬 어때?
Fine.
What about the birds?
글쎄, 새 문양은
식사하기 좀 그렇지 않아?
I don't know. They don't say,
" Hello, sit here. Eat something. "
네가 골라
-You pick one.
-Okay. How about the ladybugs?
무당벌레는 어때?
새 무늬는 싫다며?
Forget about the birds, but big red
insects suggest fine dining.
뻘건 곤충이 보이면
밥맛도 나겠다
- 좋아, 그럼 새 무늬로 해
- 실은, 나도 별로야
-Fine! Want the birds? Get the birds!
-Not like that, I won't.
킵이라면 좋아했겠지
Kip would have liked the birds.
안녕
- 안녕, 피비
- 뭐해?
-Hi, Pheebs.
-What's going on?
너 이사가니?
-Are you moving out?
-l' m getting ready for the weekend.
아니, 주말 여행
준비하고 있어
이틀이 아니라 한 달이었니?
Are your weekends longer
than two days?
아니, 내 짐은 얼마 안돼
파올로 짐도 있어
These aren't all my suitcases.
This one's Paolo's.
우리 잠깐 얘기 좀 할까?
-Rachel, can we talk for a sec?
-Well, sure.
그래, 빨리 해
파올로가 오는 중이야
Just for a sec, Paolo's on his way.
아, 그래!
알았어
- 피비, 피비
- 알았어
우리가 오랜 친구는 아니지만
We haven't known each other that long.
네가 알아야 할게 3가지 있어
There are three things
you should know:
첫째, 친구는 내 인생의 전부다
One, my friends are the most
important thing in my life.
둘째, 난 거짓말을 안 한다
Two, I never lie.
셋째, 건포도 과자는 내가 최고다
And three, I make the best
oatmeal raisin cookies in the world.
그래, 고마워
Okay. Thanks, Pheebs.
세상에!
-Oh, my God!
-I know.
왜 진작 안 만들었어?
Why have I never tasted these?
자주 안 만들어
다른 과자들이 기죽을까봐
I don't make them a lot, because
it's not fair to the other cookies.
네 말이 맞구나
내가 먹어본 과자 중에 최고야
These are the best
oatmeal raisin cookies.
- 거봐, 거짓말 안 하지?
- 진짜 그래
-Which proves that I never lie.
-I guess you don't.
파올로가 찝쩍댔어
Paolo made a pass at me.
자, 어때?
What do you think?
- 정말 너무 아름다운 탁자다
- 맞아
It's the most beautiful table
I've seen.
I know.
사용 방법 좀 알려줘
접시 균형만 잘 잡으면 돼?
Will you balance plates
on these heads?
식사는 싱크대에서 할거야
Who cares? We'll eat at the sink.
Come on!
오빠, 머리 치워
Heads up, Ross.
골인! 한방에 갔지?
Score! You suck!
괜찮니?
Are you okay?
우유가 필요해
I need some mik.
우유도 가져왔어
Okay. I've got milk.
마셔
Here you go.
좀 낫니?
Better?
아니
No.
바보가 된 기분이야
I feel so stupid! I think about
the other day with you guys.
전에 친구들 앞에서
우리 파올로 너무 멋지지 않니?
그랬잖아
And I was all, " Oh, Paolo!
He's so great!
He makes me feel so"
God!
너무 창피해
I' m so embarrassed!
난 더 창피해
I' m so embarrassed.
유혹을 못 이겼잖아
-l' m the one he hit on.
-I unleashed him on you.
- 내 잘못이야
- 아니, 내 잘못이야
내가 그이를 안 만났으면
이런 일은 없었겠지
If I had never met him
- 미안해, 아냐, 피비, 미안해
- 내가 미안해, 아니, 미안해
-l' m so sorry.
-No, l' m sorry.
-l' m sorry.
-l' m sorry. Wait.
잠깐,
왜 우리가 사과하는 거야?
-What are we sorry about?
-I don't know.
몰라, 맞아
나쁜 놈은 따로 있는데
Right. He's the pig.
- 나쁜 놈!
- 정말 나쁜 놈이야!
-Such a pig!
-Oh, God, he's such a pig!
- 그 놈은 정말...
- 아주 역겨운 놈이야
He's like a big disgusting pig....
- 돼지 같은 놈!
- 그래, 그거야
-Pig man!
-Yes, good!
그래도 내 돼지야
But he was my pig man!
왜 눈치도 못 챘을까?
How did I not see this?
난 알아
Oh, I know!
왜냐면, 잘생긴데다
매력적이잖아
Because...
... he's gorgeous.
And he's charming.
그 사람이 널 볼 때...
-And when he looks
-Okay, Pheebs.
- 됐어, 피비
- 끝!
The end.
어쩌지?
God.
내가 괜히 말했나봐
Should I not have told you?
아냐, 잘했어
내가 아는 게 낫지
T rust me, it's much better
that I know.
그래도 기분은 나쁘다
예전에 좋았잖아
But I just liked it better before.
It was better.
잘 견딜 수 있을 거야
She took it pretty well.
Paolo's over there now, so....
지금 파올로가 와 있으니까...
가서 괜찮은지 보고와
We should go and see if she's okay.
Just one second.
아주 잠깐만
또 골인!
우리가 이겼다
-Score!
-Game! Nice!
가보자
Come on, Pheebs.
Well, it looks like we
kicked your butts.
우리 때문에 애 좀 먹었지?
아니, 모니카가 이긴 거야
넌 그냥 멍청히 서있었잖아
She did. You could be on the Olympic
"Standing There" team.
그럼 2대 1로 붙어
Come on. Two on one.
여기서 뭐 하는 거야?
지금 막 헤어졌어
네가 가서 잡아
Why are you here?
She just broke up with him.
It's time for you to swoop in.
지금?
-What, now?
-Yes. Now is when you swoop.
지금이 기회야
파올로가 떠나고 레이첼이
처음 보는 남자가 너야
When Paolo walks out,
you gotta be the first guy she sees.
넌 완전히 다른 남자인 거야
파올로와 정반대로 보인다구
She's gotta know you' re everything
he's not. You' re the anti-Paolo.
매우 뛰어난 이론이야
My Catholic friend is right.
She's distraught.
You' re there for her.
가서 레이첼을 위로해
You pick up the pieces and then
you usher in "The Age of Ross. "
마음을 추스려 주고
그 맘속에 로스를 심어버려
알았어, 그만 좀 해
-See this? See?
-Hold it! Ascolta!
상황이 어때?
보지마
이제 파올로 옷은 다 던졌어
-How's it going?
-Don't stare.
She threw his clothes off the balcony.
Now there's gesturing and arm-waving.
온갖 표현이 난무할 거야
어떻게 그럴 수가!
넌 가슴이 이뻐
That is, " How could you? "
or " Enormous breasts! "
나온다
Here he comes.
그럼... 잘들 있어
I am...
...to say goodbye.
그래, 잘 가
Okay, bye-bye.
파올로
Paolo, I really hate you for what you
did, but I still have five of these...
네가 한 짓을
생각하면 미워죽겠어
많이 남았으니까 가져가
뜨거우니까 입천장 조심하구
...so heat it at 375
until the cheese bubbles.
고마워
너에게 할 말이 있는데...
모두에게 소문 내 줄게
I just wanna tell you, and I think
I'd speak for everyone when I say....
쟤 좀 봐
Oh, just look at her.
우리 모두가 몰려가면
창피해 할지도 몰라
Guys, I think only one of us
should go...
-...so she's not overwhelmed.
-Right.
맞아
나 혼자 가볼게
And I really think it should be me.
안녕
기분 어때?
훨씬 나아
You all right?
I've been better.
믿을 수가 없어
I don't believe this.
이 남자를 좋아한 게 실수야
I wasn't supposed to care
about this guy.
한때 지나간 남자로
생각하면 돼
It was just supposed to be
this big, fun, ltalian thing.
나중에 추억거리로 말하겠지
그때 진짜 웃긴 녀석이 있었지!
Someday I could look back and say,
"That was a big, fun, ltalian thing. "
그래도 이런 이별은
상상도 못했어
It wasn't supposed to feel
like this when it was over.
이리 와
Come here.
그런 녀석은 너에게
어울리지 않아
Listen...
...you deserve
so much better than him.
네가 얼마나 좋은 여자인지
알아주는 남자를 만나야 돼
I mean, you...
...should be with a guy who knows
what he has when he has you.
로스...
왜?
What?
이제 남자라면 지겨워!
아무도 만나고 싶지 않아
I' m so sick of guys!
I don't want to look at
or think about another guy.
만날 생각도 없고
남자 근처에 가기도 싫어
I don't even want
to be near another guy.
넌 정말 좋은 사람이야
Ross, you' re so great.
- 괜찮아?
- 괜찮니?
-Are you all right?
-Are you okay?
그저 그래
-Medium. Any cookies left?
-Yeah.
- 과자 남은 거 있니?
- 응
모든 남자를 부정하는 건
좋은 답이 아냐
See, Rach...
... I don't think swearing off guys
altogether is the answer.
네가 필요한 건 남자 보는
눈을 넓혀야 하는 거야
What you need is to develop a more
sophisticated screening process.
아냐, 한동안은 혼자 있고 싶어
생각할 시간이 필요해
I just need to be by myself
for a while.
-I just gotta figure out what I want.
-No, no.
아니, 안돼
모든 남자들이 파올로
같지는 않아
See, because not all guys out there
are gonna be a Paolo.
그래, 나도 알아
네 아들은 착하게 클 거야
No, I know. I know.
And l' m sure your little boy's
not gonna grow up to be one.
- 뭐?
-What?
내가 아들을 갖는다구?
I' m having a boy?
No.
아니, 아냐
아들이란 말이 아니라...
No. In fact, you' re not having a boy.
내가 아들을 갖는다니...
내... 내가 아들을 가져?
I' m having a boy.
-Huh? Am I having a boy?
-You' re having a boy!
그래, 아들이래!
- 아들이래!
- 그래
아들이란다!
I' m having a boy!
뭐야? 왜 그래?
-l' m having a boy!
-What is it?
아기가 아들이래!
내가 아들을 갖는다구
I' m having a boy!
우린 알고 있었어
We already knew that!
아들이 나온대!
I' m having a son.
좋았어,
잘 좀 막지!
Yes! And that would be a shutdown!
니 입이나 막아!
Shutout!
왜 그래?
한 판만 더 해
Where you going? One more game!
새벽 2시 반이야
-It's 2:30 in the morning.
-Yeah, get out!
집에 가
맨날 내 아파트에서
놀 땐 언제고?
You guys always hang out
in my apartment.
한 손으로 상대해 줄게
I'll only use my left hand.
그래도 겁나?
Come on, wussies!
알았어, 간다, 가
All right! Okay! I gotta go!
I' m going.
이제 시원해?
And l' m gone.
- 한판 더?
- 좋지
-One more game?
-Oh, yeah.